System engineer

Anthony BESCOND

Mobile: +33 (0)6 87 79 01 99 30 years old

Email: besconda(at)gmail.com Online: https://redref.github.io/self-resume/



Over ten years in system and applications administration, I acquired a global understanding of differents ways to integrate, push to production and run applications. Those various IT domains and experiences permit me to quickly learn and work in autonomy on new technologies and challenges.

I am looking forward to integrate a new infrastructure and new challenges always with performance, scalability and simplicity in mind.

Skills and Technologies

Configuration management: Puppet, CI/CD **Monitoring:** OpenTSDB, Graphite, ELK, Nagios **Development:** system daemons, micro-services, APIs

Languages: Python, Shell, Javascript, ...

BigData: Hadoop, Elasticsearch, Cassandra, ...

HPC: Slurm, Infiniband, Paraview **Storage:** Ceph, MooseFS, NFS

Education

Professional degree (Licence) in "Networks administration and security"

2008

Technology degree (DUT) in "Networks and telecommunications"

2007

Experiences

System engineer in HPC/BigData

depuis 2014

Ministry of defense (Paris)

Technologies: Puppet, Linux, Python, Django, DRF, Ceph, Infiniband, GPU

Choose hardware according to software benchmarks and problems. Provision, configure, patch and maintain "bare metal" hardware clusters. Integrate and optimise HPC and BigData softwares for performance. Design and develop tools as daemons, APIs or webservices to manage platforms (Python)

Analyse customers applications to optimise workloads.

System engineer in e-commerce

2013 à 2014

Galeries Lafayette (Paris)

Technologies: Apache, Varnish, Tomcat, Oracle, Hybris, Graphite

Manage and maintain the 3-tier web platform and product publishing workflows. Design and maintain delivery architecture with test platforms and automatic build

processes.

Integrate metrology tools used by the platform capacity planning and marketing.

System engineer in HPC

2013

OVH GS - Oxalya (Paris)

Technologies: Linux, Slurm, Lustre, Infiniband, GPU Nvidia

Install, deploy and maintain dedicated HPC clusters in customers offices.

Integrate a "software as a service" offer.

Compile, optimise and benchmark computation softwares.

System administrator

2010 à 2012

DCNS (Cherbourg)

Technologies: Linux, Oracle, JBOSS, Apache, Tomcat, Java, Centreon; Control-

Install and maintain industrial applications (stock and workflows) and daily data

Develop tools to ensure a safe and smooth delivery installation process.

System administrator "Intelligent Network"

2008 à 2010

Alcatel-Lucent

Assignments: Bell M (Canada), OTE (Grèce), Orange (R.Dominicaine).

Technologies: Solaris, Oracle, Switching

Install and deliver IN application cluster and services on customer site.

Network administrator (internship)

2008

MMF Services (Quéven)

Configure new network stack with internal needs. Integrate web-services as alternatives to VPN.

PHP developer (internship)

2007

Solstys (Lannion)

Integrate WebDav protocol in the CMS product by emulation in PHP.

Interests

Trail running

Development and new technologies (home system, deep learning algorithms, ...) Online gaming